Ed Millington

Location: Christchurch, NZ **E**

Email: ed@edmill.dev

Github: github.com/mllnqtn

Web: <u>edmill.dev</u>

Profile

Hi! My name's Ed and I'm a senior front-end developer based in Christchurch, New Zealand. I love to build websites and apps that are **beautiful**, **fast**, **accessible** and **standards-compliant**. I have been a professional developer since 2012, having originally come into the field via a background in music and interactive art.

Aside from writing and reviewing high-quality code, I believe that a good front-end developer should act as an **advocate for the end user**. That means prioritising elegant UI and intuitive UX solutions, while ensuring that releases are usable on all devices, from screen-reader equipped desktops to mobile phones with spotty data connections.

I have spent the last year living in Vancouver, Canada, and will return to New Zealand in December 2023. During my time in Canada, I have worked part-time as a freelancer while also raising my daughter, who was born in March 2022. I'm now looking for a new, full-time challenge at a company which will allow me to put my existing expertise to use in an environment of continued technological and process improvement.

Skills

Primary skills:

HTML & CSS / SASS

JavaScript

Vue

React / React Native

Git

Favourite Tools:

Vite / Parcel

Gulp

Docker

VoiceOver

Experience of working with:

RESTful APIs

GraphQL

PHP for Wordpress / Silverstripe

Adobe Photoshop & XD

Node.js and npm

Core methodologies:

BEM

Functional JS

Agile development

DRY code

Work Experience

2016 - 2022

Senior front-end developer: TimeZoneOne, Christchurch NZ

timezoneone.com

TimeZoneOne is a full-service digital agency with offices in Chicago, IL and Christchurch, NZ. I joined the company as an intermediate developer in 2016, progressing to senior level in 2019. During my there, I:

- Collaborated as part of a cross-discipline team, developing and maintaining web and hybrid apps for a broad range of clients.
- Implemented best practices for accessibility: a number of our clients were funded by the US government, and so were required to hit WCAG AA compliance as a minimum.
- Was involved with clients at all stages of the product life-cycle, including on-going maintenance.
- Led initiatives to continually update our coding best-practice. In 2022, I led development of an update to the agency's in-house boilerplate for web projects. This update:
 - increased our indicative mobile performance score on Lighthouse from 40 to 93
 - increased our indicative accessibility score from 72 to 100
 - decreased our generated CSS by 75%
 - decreased our generated JS by 50%
 - replaced monolithic, render-blocking downloads with dynamic imports

2015 - 2016

Web developer & digital designer: Intohand, Bath UK

Intohand was a digital agency which primarily built mobile and tablet apps for enterprise clients. I designed, built & maintained the CMS and storefront websites which accompanied these apps, as well being involved in the design of the UI and UX of the apps themselves.

2012 - 2015

E-book developer: MACK Books, London UK

MACK Books is an independent publishing house, specialising in art and photography. I designed and built enhanced e-books for artists, curators and museums.

mackbooks.co.uk

Education

2012	University of Glamorgan	PGCert: Programming for the web, handheld devices and new media [distinction]
2011	Royal Welsh College of Music & Drama	MMus: Creative Music Technology [distinction]
2007	Durham University	BA (Hons): Classical Past [1st]